A Guide to the Russell Sage Foundation records, SG 3 FA413
Rockefeller Archive Center
Russell Sage Foundation records, SG 3
1965-2016
Rockefeller Archive Center
Russell Sage Foundation
FA413
48.23 Cubic Feet 127 letter document boxes
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Russell Sage Foundation records donated to Rockefeller Archive Center by Eric Wanner, RSF President, April 2010.
Conditions Governing Access
Records 15 years old or older are open for research, with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.
Scope and Contents
Grant administration records including grant letter, budget, correspondence, reports, and associated publications or grant products.
- Grants, 1965-2016; 1; 48.23 Cubic Feet 127 letter document boxes
  Arrangement
  Intellectually arranged by program/topic.
  Scope and Contents
  Grant administration records including grant letter, budget, correspondence, reports, and associated publications or grant products.
  - Behavioral Economics
    - Acland and Chow - Behavioral and Psychological Factors in Online Game Playing (98-09-06), 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alexander and Christia - Ethnic Diversity and Contribution to Public Goods (98-06-22), 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Allegreto and Reich - Tipped Subminimum Wages: Earnings and Employment Effects (85-15-03), 2014 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Restricted - Open in 2030
    - Anaqol and Gamble - Framing Background Risk to Induce Greater Risk Taking in Stocks (98-08-10), 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ashton - Hunger Games - How Does Hunger Affect Economic Decisions (98-14-01), 2013-2015 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Conditions Governing Access
    - Atanasov - Commit to Submit - Assessing the Power of Social and Financial Commitments (98-11-03), 2010-2014 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Atanassova - The Right Incentives - Gender and Motivational Strategies in a Public Goods Setting (98-07-03), 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Atkin - Behavioral Responses to Differential Timing of Pension Distribution - Evidence from South Africa--AWARD CANCELLED (98-06-23), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Azar - Relative Thinking - Does it Exist with Real Choices (98-06-13), 2005-2009 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Baldiga - Gender and Expertise (98-13-03), 2012-2014 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Beaman and Magruder - How Job Networks Work - A Study Using Experimental and Behavioral Economics (98-08-15), 2007-2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Benjamin and Shapiro - Bounded Cognition and Economic Decision Making (98-04-06), 2003-2008 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Berry - Parental Commitment and Child Motivation in Educational Decisions (98-07-13), 2007-2009 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bertrand and Mullainathan - Decision Making Under Poverty: A Behavioral Research Program (98-03-03), 2003-2006 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bhargava and Wu - Contract Effects in Medical Decision Making (8-09-09), 2009-2010 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Blattman - Stolen Children, Shattered Lives - A Study of the Impact of Abduction and Soldiering on the Children of Sudan and Uganda (98-06-09), 2005-2007 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Bloemraad - Organizing for Political Voice: Role of Community Organizations in Immigrant Political Incorporation (88-05-10), 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Borden - Evaluation of Weather Patterns by Cruise Ship Customers and Future Consumption Decisions (98-06-10), 2005-2006 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Breza - Trust, Punishment, and Networks - Evidence from a Lab Experiment in the Field (98-11-09), 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Bryan - Altruism and Obligation (98-09-18), 2009-2010 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Bursztyn - Herding Beyond Learning - Opening the Black Box of Peer Effects in Financial Decisions (98-12-08), 2011-2013 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Restricted - Open in 2029
    - Campante - Behavioral Economics and Economists' Behavior (98-07-06), 2007-2010 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Carvalho - Learning to Have Self-Control: The Effect of Savings on Present Bias (98-11-14), 2011-2013 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Chao - Much Obligated: When and How Gifts Induce Reciprocity (98-13-06), 2012-2014 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Chen - The Economics of Religious Fundamentalism (98-05-08), 2005-2008 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Chen - Understanding the Incentives for Microfinance Lending (98-14-03), 2013-2015 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Chen - Exploring Primate Trading Behavior, 2005-2008 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Cho - The Effect of Self-Identity Activation on Behaviors in the Dictator and Ultimatum Games (98-06-20), 2006-2009 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Choi - Identity and Preferences (98-06-15), 2006-2008 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Congdon - Using Behavioral Insights to Improve Federal Communications (98-13-11), 2013-2014 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Coutts - Belief Biases with Financial Stakes (98-14-06), 2014 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Dawes - The Role of Genetics in Preference Formation (98-06-18), 2006-2007 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Dizon-Ross - How Does Parental Overconfidence Affect Educational Attainment - Evidence from a Randomized Controlled Trial in Malawi (98-12-06), 2011-2013 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Derksen - Providing Information on Antiretrovirals and HIV Transmission - An Intervention to Reduce Stigma and Promote Testing (98-14-07), 2014-2015 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Durham - Stanford University Program in Medicine and the Behavioral Sciences, 1965-1999 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Elbel - Choice Sets and Consumer Selection of Health Plans (98-06-16), 2006-2010 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Eli-Rao - Self-Image and Signal Interference (98-09-10), 2009-2010 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Enke - Correlation Neglect in Belief Formation (98-13-02), 2012-2013 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Ericson - Expectations as Endowments - The Impact of Reference-Dependent Preferences on Exchange Behavior (98-09-19), 2009-2010 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Ericson - A Test for Inequality Aversion Using Social Gambles (98-08-13), 2008-2010 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Hershfield - The Vividness of Your Future Self - Using Immersive Virtual Reality to Increase Retirement Saving (98-09-03), 2008-2010 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Ertac - The Value and Acquisition of Ego-Relevant Information - An Experimental Study (98-05-11), 2005-2006 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Ertac - The Informational Role of Social Comparisons (98-06-01), 2005-2008 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Evans - The Mental Costs of Trust and Reciprocity (98-09-07), 2008-2010 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Esteves-Sorenson - The Role of Expectations in the Intrinsic-Extrinsic Incentives Trade-Off: Is the Crowding Out a Fallacy? (98-11-10), 2011-2012 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Ferreira - What to Expect When They Are Expecting - The Role of Expectations on Labor Market Reciprocity (98-14-10), 2014-2015 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Fischer - Contract Structure, Risk Sharing, and Investment Choice (98-07-09), 2007-2010 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Fletcher - Identification with School the Key Component in the "Black Box" of Education Outcomes (98-06-12), 2005-2008 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Fowler - Turnout and the Dictator - How Altruism Affects Political Participation (98-05-06), 2004-2008 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Gosh - Price Manipulation by the Auctioneer - An Experimental Study (98-07-12), 2007-2009 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Greenberg - Gender Gap in Negotiation Outcomes - Experiments on the Bargaining Setting (98-15-03), 2014-2016 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Restricted - Open in 2031
    - Grossman - The Role of Information in Motivating Giving (98-08-07), 2008-2009 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Guney - An Experiment on Aspiration Based Choice (98-10-13), 2010-2013 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Gunnsteinsson - Trust - Formation and Social Learning, 98-12-12, 2012-2013 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Paci - AWARD DECLINED - Reference-Dependent Fraud (98-14-05), 2013-2014 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Hamman - Self-Interest through Agency (98-06-03), 2005-2010 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Hanna - Farmer Experimentation and Learning (98-07-10), 2007-2009 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Hayashi - Fairness and Just Allocation of Economic Resources (98-08-14), 2008-2010 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Hjort - Instant Trauma - Individual Productivity, Indirect Shocks and Team Composition, 98-09-05, 2009-2010 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Hoffman - The Demand for Information on the Internet: Evidence from Field Experiments (98-09-20), 2009-2012 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Hoffman - Improving Targeting through Non-Monetary Costs (98-13-04), 2012-2014 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Hsu - Your Own Worst Enemy: Overconfidence and Escalation in a Fantasy Baseball Field Experiment (98-06-26), 2006-2008 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Jahedi - A Taste for Bargains (98-08-04), 2007-2009 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Jakiela - Why Do Property Rights Matter (98-06-19), 2006-2007 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Jeon - Costly Punishment Across Ethnic Boundaries (98-11-11), 2011-2013 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Jones, Arthur - Advance Earned Income Tax Credit (98-06-17), 2006-2008 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - RSF - Special Journal Issue on Consumer Finance (98-10-15), 2009-2012 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Karkoviata - Migrant Savings and Banking Behavior (98-07-07), 2007-2011 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Kartik - When Would I Lie to You (98-07-04), 2006-2008 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Kelly - Why and When Does Question Specificity Affect Prediction Quality (98-14-11), 2014-2016 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy - Behavioral and Experimental Economics in Mongolia (98-08-01), 2007-2009 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Kerwin - Exploring Potential Fatalism in the Response of Malawians' Sexual Behavior to HIV Transmission Risks (98-12-13), 2012-2013 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Kline - Income Inequality, Inequity, and Corruption (98-11-05), 2010-2012 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Krumme - Tangible Aids to Unitize Action and Improve Decision-Making (AWARD CANCELLED) (98-10-04), 2009-2010 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Lacetera - Incentives and Pro-Social Behavior: The Case of Blood Donation (8-08-08), 2008-2009 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Laibson-Rabin - Behavioral Economics Summer Institute VII (98-06-21), 2006-2007 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Laibson-Madrian - Commitment Savings and Self Control (98-10-11), 2010-2011 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Landeo - Tort Reform and Disputes Under Endogenous Preferences (98-05-07), 2005-2006 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Lee, Dong - Industry Comovement after Joining an Index - Spillovers of Nonfundamental Effects (98-05-04), 2005-2007 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Lee, Jean - Discrimination in Juries in the Deliberation of Criminal Cases - GRANT DECLINED (98-08-13), 2008 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Levine - Lie unto Others as You Would Have Others Lie to You - Community Standards of Deception (98-16-01), 2014-2015 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Li - Can We Trust the (Future) Doctors - Altruistic Preferences and Specialty Choice of Medical Students (98-14-14), 2014-2015 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Lierl - What Explains Efficient Intra-Household Decision Making - Proposal for a Field Experiment in Tanzania (98-12-11), 2012-2014 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Loewenstein - The Role of Visceral Motivation in Economic Theory and Economic Behavior (98-00-11), 1999-2003 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Loewenstein - Reunion of Summer Institute on Emotion and Decision Making (98-05-10), 2005-2008 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Lusher - College Better - Parimutuel Betting Markets as a Commitment Device and Monetary Incentive (98-15-10), 2015-2016 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Lynch - Analogical Reasoning and Trade Attitudes (98-08-06), 2008-2009 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Lynham - Incentive Structures and Procrastination (98-07-05), 2007-2008 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - MacKillop - The Neuroeconomics of Tobacco Dependence (98-07-08), 2007-2009 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Magen - The Hidden Zero Effect - Reducing Rates of Temporal Discounting (98-08-11), 2008-2009 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Mayraz - An Experimental Test of a Theoretical Model of Payoff-Dependent Beliefs Distortion (98-10-03), 2009-2011 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - McCasland - The Psychology of Corruption - Moral Reminders, Social Preferences and the Kenyan Postal Service (98-10-14), 2010-2012 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - McConnell - Encouraging Investment in Health Technology (98-09-14), 2009-2011 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - McGuire - The Psychological Cost of Lying - An Experimental Investigation (98-08-09), 2008-2009 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - McManus - Show of Smarts - Audience Effects and Revealed Preferences for Perceived Effects (98-13-07), 2013-2014 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Milkman, Katherine - A Study of Discrimination and Intertemporal Choice (98-10-08), 2010-2013 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Min - Understanding Consumer Preferences for Energy Efficient Lighting Products (98-12-02), 2011-2014 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Mollerstrom - Understanding the Disposition Effect - An Experimental Approach (98-11-07), 2010-2012 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Moreno Gonzalez - Learning Under Ambiguity - An Experiment (98-12-09), 2012-2013 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Mostafa - Myopic Risk Seeking (98-05-09), 2005-2008 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Mukherjee - Social Identity and Aspirations (98-13-05), 2013-2014 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Mullainathan - Working Group on Prescriptive Economics (98-06-07), 2003-2008 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - National Research Council - Panel Study on Re-entry of Convicts, 2000-2003 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Nave - Testing the Causal Influence of Testosterone on Preferences for Competition (98-14-13), 2014-2015 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Nelson, Rob - The Endowment Effect, Framing, and Public Good Provision (98-02-02, 2002-2003 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Nikolov - Are Individual Risk Preferences Time Inconsistent - Temporal Construal and Time-Dependent Changes in Risk Preference (98-11-08), 2011-2012 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Ngatia - Social Interactions and Individual Reproductive Decisions (98-11-12), 2011-2014 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Nguyen - Poverty, Inequality and Social Preferences in Vietnam - Field Experiments (98-06-06), 2005-2006 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Nolen - Self-Efficacy and Influences of Performance (98-06-05), 2005-2007 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Offenberg (Pate) - Asymmetry and Incomplete Information in an Experimental Volunteer's Dilemma (98-07-01), 2006-2008 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Ogawa - Separating the Screening, Signaling, and Sunk-Cost Effects of Price (98-12-07), 2011-2013 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Okeke - An Empirical Investigation of the Demand for Prevention - An Analysis of Cervical Cancer Screenings (98-08-16), 2008-2012 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Lynham - Incentive Structures and Procrastination (98-07-05), 2007-2008 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Olson, Jenny - An Experimental Test of the Benefits of Utilizing Joint Accounts in Marriage (98-13-01), 2012-2015 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Papp - Decision Making Among Migrants in Rural India (98-11-02), 2009-2012 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Park, Young Joon - Self-Image in Objective Qualities (98-06-11), 2005-2006 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Patterson - Identifying and Addressing Self-Control Problems for Online Students - Evidence from a Field Experiment (98-14-08), 2014-2015 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Perez-Truglia - Testing Conspicuous Consumption in the Lab (98-11-06), 2010-2013 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Pomeranz - Peer Effects in Savings - Evidence from a Randomized Field Experiment (98-10-09), 2010-2012 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Pons - Registering Unregistered Voters - Evidence from a Randomized Experiment in France (98-12-03), 2012-2013 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Pope - Advanced Placement Tests and Procrastination (98-05-03), 2005-2007 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Potamites - Emotions and Investment Behavior on Trading Floors in China (98-06-14), 2006-2007 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Preston - Can Behavior in Laboratory Experiments Explain Gender Differences in Labor Market Outcomes (98-12-14), 2012-2015 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Prina - Self-Control and Nutritional Knowledge - What Influences Children's Food Consumption (98-09-02), 2009-2010 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Taubinsky - Policy Implications of Tax Salience - Measuring and Modeling Heterogeneity and Tax Size Effects (98-15-07), 2015 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Rabin - Psychology and Economics - A Textbook for Behavioral Economics (98-98-03), 1996-2004 (Box 98, Folder 4-5)
    - Rick - Effects of Spending Cues on Spendthrifts and Tightwads (98-06-08), 2005-2007 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Robinson - National Identification and Interpersonal Trust in a Diverse Society (98-11-13), 2011-2013 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Restricted - Open in 2028
    - Savani - Affective Conditioning of Uncertain Prospects (98-08-12), 2008-2009 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Schaner - Private Savings, Intrahousehold Bargaining, and Intertemporal Consumption Choices (98-09-08), 2009-2013 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Schechter - The Value of Networks (98-06-24), 2006-2011 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Sequeira - Entrepreneurial Networking and the Economics of Discrimination (98-10-12), 2010-2012 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Shafir - The Behavioral Foundations of Policy (98-08-05), 2007-2012 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Shtauber - The Effects of Access to Mainstream Financial Services on the American Poor (98-12-10), 2012-2013 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Shoag - Behavioral Investment Biases in Public DB and DC Pension Plans (98-12-04), 2011-2013 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Small - Identifiability (98-03-01), 2003-2004 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Shafir - Award Terminated - The Psychology of Scarcity (98-15-01), 2014-2015 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Shapiro - Mental Accounting and Fungibility of Money - Evidence from a Retail Panel (98-15-09), 2015 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Smeiser - The Handbook of Economic Sociology, Second Edition (98-01-04), 2001-2005 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Song - Media and Social Networks in Uganda (98-09-16), 2009-2013 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Stevenson - Present-Bias, Peer Effects, and Economic Outcomes (98-13-09), 2013-2014 (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - Stockley - Expectation-Based Reference Points and Effort Provision: Does History Matter - Proposal for a Framed-Field Experiment (98-14-12), 2013-2015 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Sullivan, Karen - The Effects of Risk, Time Preference, and Poverty on the Impacts of Forest Property Right Reform (98-09-11), 2009-2010 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Sydnor - A Field Experiment on the Effectiveness of Commitment Contracts (98-09-01), 2008-2009 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Tanaka - Nature of Racial Discrimination - Inter-Ethnic Field Experiments (98-06-25), 2006-2010 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Tasoff - Over optimism About Future Performance - Evidence from Rebate Redemption Experiments (98-11-01), 2011-2012 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Tomlin - Social Recognition and Altruistic Preferences (98-09-04), 2009-2010 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Uler - Understanding Social Sharing Norms between the U.S. and Europe (98-09-15), 2009-2012 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Kriss - Social Approval and Communication in the Dictator Game - Theory and Experiment (98-12-05), 2011-2013 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Vul - Measuring the Crowd Within - Probabilistic Cognition in Economic Decision Making (98-08-02), 2007-2009 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Wang - Corruption and Selection into Public Service - An Experimental Study in the Field (98-09-13), 2009-2013 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Wherry - Pilot Study of Lending Circles and Financial Inclusion among Lower-Income Immigrants and Minorities - The Mechanisms of Behavior Change (98-15-02), 2014-2016 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Williams - Why Do Women Shy Away from Competition - The Effects of Information on the Choice to Compete (98-09-17), 2009-2011 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Xandri - Is Bayesian Learning or Naive-Preferential Weighting a Better Approximation of Learning on Networks (98-10-02), 2010-2011 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Xiao - Punish in Private and Praise in Public (98-07-02), 2006-2009 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Yoeli - Social Pressure and the Demand for Green Products (98-08-03), 2007-2010 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Zheng - Trust in Strategic Information Communication - The Impact of Culture (8-10-10), 2010-2011 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Zinman - Behavioral Biases in Household Financial Decision-Making (98-11-04), 2010-2015 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Care Work
    - Folbre - Care Time - Improving Measurement and Valuation (85-12-03), 2011-2015 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Gornick and Presser - Who's Minding Their Kids - U.S. Child Care Workers' Child Care Arrangements - An Assessment Using the SIPP (85-12-04), 2011-2013 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Kristin - Wages, Scheduling Flexibility, and Job Benefits in Care Occupations - Perquisites or Tradeoffs (85-12-06), 2012-2014 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Wolf - Do State-Level Policy Choices Influence Caregiver Behavior (85-12-02), 2012-2014 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Census
    - RSF - Consortium Membership in the New York Census Research Data Center (84-02-01), 2002-2008 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Haaga - Understanding America in the New Century - Analysis and Informed Use of the 2000 Census (84-99-02), 1999-2005 (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
    - Hout - Supplemental Appropriation - USA - A Century of Difference (84-99-03), 1999-2006 (Box 51, Folder 5-6)
    - Maury - America's Scorecard - The Historic Role of the Census in an Ever-Changing Nation (84-04-01), 2003-2004 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Consumer Finance
    - Barr - Conference on Financial Reform (98-14-09), 2014-2015 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Skiba - Check Cashing - Time Preferences, Income Variability and Rationality among the Unbanked (98-10-06), 2010-2013 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Sydnor - How Much House Can We Afford - An Experimental Analysis of the Factors that Influence Household Decision-Making about Housing Purchases (98-10-07), 2010-2013 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Cross-National Research on the Intergenerational Transmission of Advantage (CRITA)
    - Corak - Families, Firms, and Labour Market Inequalities - The Long Run Consequences of the Intergenerational Transmission of Employers (83-09-09), 2007-2010 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - RSF - Additional Data Collection and Analysis for the CRITA Project (Added to Overall Project Appropriation) (83-10-07), 2010 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Smeeding - Cross-National Research on the Intergenerational Transmission of Advantage (Project Appropriation) (83-09-06), 2009-2011 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Cross-National Research on the Intergenerational Transmission of Advantage (CRITA), 2009-2010 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Frick - Intergenerational Research Based on the German Socio-Economic Panel Study (SOEP) (83-09-12), 2009-2012 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Jantti - Parental Resources, Child Health, Ability, and Schooling and Own Income - Sweden and the United States Compared (83-09-13), 2009-2012 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Jonsson - Cognitive and Non-Cognitive Mediators in the Earnings Mobility Process (83-09-14), 2009-2012 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Katz - Have Policy Changes Affected the Early Mobility of Children from Different Backgrounds in Australia (83-09-15), 2009-2012 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Micklewright - Parental Socio-Economic Status and Children's Cognitive Achievement at Ages 9 and 15 - How Do the Links Vary Across the Countries (83-09-18), 2009-2010 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Smeeding - Child Development and Social Mobility: U.S. and Canada (83-09-19), 2009-2010 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Waldfogel - A Cross-Country Study of the Effect of Parental Resources and Public Policies on Inequality in Early Child Outcomes (83-09-20), 2010-2012 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Westergard-Nielson - Intergenerational Mobility in Denmark (83-09-21), 2009 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Cultural Contact
    - Aronson - Stereotype Threat - Understanding and Reducing the Negative Effects of Inter-Ethnic Contact on Academic Performance (87-99-01), 1998-2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)